# Senthurbayan Kirubaharan

് +94 77 035 4631 | ☑ senthurbavankiruba@gmail.com | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/senthurbavan github.com/Senthurbavan

## Research Interests

My research interest revolves around robotics, particularly in navigation, both classical and AI methods, and multi-robot coordination. I am currently working on navigation and have previous research experience on power optimization for ROS-based autonomous mobile robots.

#### EDUCATION

University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka Feb. 2016 - Jan. 2020

BSc.,  $Electronic \ \ \ \ \ Telecommunication \ Engineering \ with \ Honors$ 

GPA: 3.81/4.2 (3.77/4.0)

## Skills

Languages: English, Tamil

Programming: Python, C/C++, VHDL, MATLAB, LATEX

Libraries: ROS, NumPy, TensorFlow

Microcontrollers: STM32, Atmel, EFM8, Arduino

Others: FPGA design, PCB design

## Research Experience

## Intellisense Lab, University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Research Engineer, E-consulate (Pvt) Ltd. Working in collaboration with Intellisense Lab

Supervised by Dr. Sulochana Sooriyaarachchi & Dr. Chandana Gamage

July 2021 - Present

The Intellisense Lab focuses on building mobile robot system for exploration. I am working on extending the current simulation work to a real-world implementation, mainly focusing on ROS navigation stack.

## Electronic & Telecom. Engineering Dept., University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Undergraduate Research, supervised by Dr. Peshala Jayasekara

Feb. 2019 - Jan. 2020

My research was on power optimization of autonomous mobile robot navigation in which I designed and developed hardware-software co-design architecture for optimizing computational power of local planner of ROS navigation stack with FPGA hardware accelerator. The resulting component is consuming less power to a degree of four and faster due to C++ implementation on Linux platform. This research is published at the ACRA 2020 conference, and I presented it as the first author.

## Working Experience

## **Embedded Research Engineer**

August 2020 - April 2021

SenzMate (Pvt) Ltd

Colombo, Sri Lanka

During the pandemic, I worked on an initiative to serve the community by building an AI COVID-19 Wristband. It detects the hand washing pattern of the user and compare it to that of the WHO standard using IMU data, and the implementation was on C, in real-time.

## Research Intern SenzMate (Pvt) Ltd

June 2018 – December 2018

Colombo, Sri Lanka

We developed a peer-to-peer bidirectional wireless communication module based on the LoRa protocol. The module works as a remote controller and virtual serial link. I was involved in the development of communication protocol for multi-point to multi-point reliable communication and firmware development.

## EEG Amplifier for Long-Term Brain Monitoring

2019

- Final year group project supervised by Dr. Simon Lind Kappel
- Developed the digital front-end to acquire signals from the analog-to-digital converter and process them
- Developed firmware for high-speed signal acquisition, data storage, and Bluetooth communication with a mobile phone for real-time monitoring

## Processor Design for Image Downsampling

2018

- $\bullet$  Designed instruction set architecture for downsampling an image by factor 2
- Designed the microarchitecture of the processor and implemented it in FPGA

Automatic Doorbell 2018

• Designed a PCB with passive infrared sensors to detect heat radiation from humans and to eliminate ambient heat radiations

# GPS Navigated Robot

2017

- Participated in a robotic competition, and built a robot with a microcontroller that should navigate through obstacles towards a GPS goal location, identify a box and get the ring placed inside
- Developed obstacle avoidance with 3 ultrasonic range sensors and built navigation component to reach the box

## Analog Line Following Robot

2017

- Designed a mobile robot solely with analog electronic circuits to follow a white line on a black surface
- Employed IR emitter and receiver to detect the white line on the black surface
- Designed a PID controller with operational amplifiers for motor speed control

#### AWARDS

Dean's List (2016, 2019)

Mahapola Higher Education Merit Scholarship (2016)

## Publications

**Senthurbavan Kirubaharan**, Peshala Jayasekara & Dilan Weerakkody. Low Power FPGA-based Hardware Accelerator for Autonomous Navigation of Mobile Robots. In 2020 Australasian Conference on Robotics and Automation (ACRA 2020). Paper link

## Reference

☑ peshala@uom.lk

## Dr. Peshala Jayasekara

Senior Lecturer
Dept. of Electronic and
Telecommunication Engineering
University of Moratuwa
Sri Lanka
+94 71 127 3844

Dr. Simon Lind Kappel

Postdoctoral researcher Dept. Electrical and Computer Engineering Aarhus University Finlandsgade 22 DK-8200 Aarhus N Denmark

**८** +45 5192 5183 ⋈ slk@ece.au.dk Dr. Sulochana Sooriyaarachchi

Senior Lecturer
Dept. of Computer Science
and Engineering
University of Moratuwa
Sri Lanka
\$\mathbb{L}\$ +94 77 669 1011

☑ sulochanas@cse.mrt.ac.lk